https://developer.apple.com/documentation/http-live-streaming/adding-alternate-media-to-a-playlist

Extended M3U

In the extended M3U, additional directives are introduced that begin with “#” and end with a colon(:) if they have parameters. Given below is a list of directives for extended M3U.

    #EXTM3U - It is the file header indicating Extended M3U and must be first line of the file.
    #EXTENC: - Text encoding. It must be the 2nd line of the file.
    #EXTINF: - Used for track information and other additional properties.
    #PLAYLIST: - The title of the playlist
    #EXTGRP: - Begin name grouping
    #EXTALB: - Album information
    #EXTART: - Album artist
    #EXTGENRE - Album Genre
    #EXTM3A - Single file playlist for album tracks or chapters.
    #EXTBYT: - File size in bytes.
    #EXTBIN: - Binary data follows.
    #EXTIMG: - Logo, Cover or other images.


HLS M3U
HLS (HTTP Live Streaming) was created by Apple to stream audio and radio to iOS devices. It is based on the UTF-8 encoded extended M3U. It was standardized as RFC 8216 in 2017 by IETF. The tags for the HLS playlist begin with “#EXT-X-”. Given below is a list of tags for HLS

    EXT-X-VERSION - Indicates the compatibility version of the file based on the media and its server.
    #EXT-X-START: - Indicates the preferred starting point for the playlist.
    #EXT-X-PLAYLIST-TYPE: - Provides the type of playlist (EVENT or VOD).
    #EXT-X-TARGETDURATION: - It specifies the maximum Segment duration.
    #EXT-X-MEDIA-SEQUENCE: - It indicates the Media Sequence Number.
    #EXT-X-INDEPENDENT-SEGMENTS - It indicates that all media samples are independent and can be decoded without other segments.
    #EXT-X-MEDIA: - It is used to relate Media Playlists that contain alternative Renditions of the same content.
    #EXT-X-STREAM-INF: - It specifies a Variant Stream that is a part of the Renditions.
    #EXT-X-BYTERANGE: - Indicates that the Media Segment is a sub-range of the resource identified by its URI.
    #EXT-X-DISCONTINUITY - Indicates discontinuity between the preceding and following media segments.
    #EXT-X-DISCONTINUITY-SEQUENCE: - It allows synchronization between different renditions of the same Variant Stream or different Variant Streams.
    #EXT-X-KEY: - Specifies how to decrypt Media Segments.
    #EXT-X-MAP: - Specifies how to obtain Media Initialization Section. It is required to parse the applicable Media Segments.
    #EXT-X-PROGRAM-DATE-TIME: - It associates the first sample of the Media Segment with an absolute date and/or time.
    #EXT-X-DATERANGE: - It associates a Data Range.
    #EXT-X-I-FRAMES-ONLY - Indicates that each Media Segment in the Playlist describes a single I-frame.
    EXT-X-I-FRAME-STREAM-INF - It indicates that the playlist file contains I-frames of Multimedia presentation.
    #EXT-X-SESSION-DATA: - It allows arbitrary session data to be carried in a Master Playlist.
    #EXT-X-SESSION-KEY: - It allows for encryption keys. The client can preload these keys without reading the playlist first.
    #EXT-X-ENDLIST - It indicates that no more Media Segments will be added to the file.


High-level features

EXT-X-VERSION
Features and usage notes

2  IV attribute of the EXT-X-KEY tag
3  Floating-point EXTINF duration values
4  EXT-X-BYTERANGE, EXT-X-I-FRAME-STREAM-INF, EXT-X-I-FRAMES-ONLY, EXT-X-MEDIA, the AUDIO and VIDEO attributes of the EXT-X-STREAM-INF tag
5  KEYFORMAT and KEYFORMATVERSIONS attributes of the EXT-X-KEY tag. The EXT-X-MAP tag. SUBTITLES media type. SAMPLE-AES encryption method EXT-X-KEY
6  CLOSED-CAPTIONS media type. Allow EXT-X-MAP for subtitle playlists
7  EXT-X-SESSION-DATA, EXT-X-SESSION-KEY, EXT-X-DATERANGE, SERVICEn values of INSTREAM-ID, AVERAGE-BANDWIDTH, FRAME-RATE, CHANNELS, and HDCP-LEVEL attributes.
8  EXT-X-GAP, EXT-X-DEFINE, Variable Substitution, VIDEO-RANGE attribute.
9  EXT-X-SKIP
10  EXT-X-SERVER-CONTROL, EXT-X-PART-INF, EXT-X-PRELOAD-HINT, EXT-X-RENDITION-REPORT, the CUE attribute of EXT-X-DATERANGE, the STABLE-RENDITION-ID of EXT-X-MEDIA, the SUPPLEMENTAL-CODECS attribute of EXT-X-STREAM-INF, and the SCORE and STABLE-VARIANT-ID attributes of EXT-X-STREAM-INF and EXT-X-I-FRAME-STREAM-INF tags
11 QUERYPARAM attribute of EXT-X-DEFINE
12  Attributes starting with ‘REQ-’




